# **Mohit M Singh**

+91 844-622-0289 | mohit.itsector@gmail.com github.com/mohitmsingh | linkedin.com/in/mohitmsingh | mohitmsingh.github.io

## **Summary**

10+ years of IT Professional experience, including 6+ years of expertise in DevOps Cloud, facilitating Agile and Lead practices over Microservices, Application Deployment & Infrastructure Upgrades, Scaling, and Optimizing mission-critical deployments over large infrastructures. Worked as on-site consultant from Europe for consecutive 2 years and successfully participated in Go-Live Production for multiple regions.

## Skill

Language/Scripting: Powershell, Bash Shell, Python

Tools: Azure DevOps, GitHub Actions, Jenkins, SAST scanning Tool like Sonarqube, codeql, GIT, JFrog Artifactory, Jira

Cloud Platform: Microsoft Azure (AZ), Amazon Web Services (AWS), Cloud Foundry

Infra as a Code: Terraform, Python Boto, Azure Biceps

Observability: OpenTelemetry, Dynatrace, ELK

Container Orchestration: Docker, Kubernetes (k8s), Helm, ArgoCD, Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS), ECS,

Google Kubernetes Engine

## Education

## RTM Nagpur University, Nagpur

July 2008 - May 2012

B.E in Electronics & Telecommunication

Percentage: 70%

#### **Correspondence (Symbiosis Centre of Distance Learning, Pune)**

July 2014 – May 2016

Post Graduate Diploma in IT Management

Percentage: 70%

# **Experience**

#### Tech Mahindra, Nagpur

June 2022 - till date

Technical Lead

- Migration of a monolithic application to microservices running on Kubernetes for AWS.
- Setup of Kubernetes services on AWS with Route53
- Setup of ECS to store the developed microservices in Docker containers.
- Use of Docker Compose as local development environment.
- Development of multiple Docker containers, each one running angular, Java Application Deployment of such containers to Kubernetes Pods.
- Setup of Kubernetes nodes with CoreOS for GPU Nvidia using cloud-config.
- Setup of Open telemetry, ELK (Elasticsearch, Fluentd & Kibana) on Kubernetes
- Deployment of ConfigMaps, Secrets and Volumes on Kubernetes
- Documentation with Markdown

#### Wipro Ltd., Pune

Dec 2021 – May 2022

Technical Lead

- Managed a DevOps team of over 15 members to complete the migration of 25+ applications to Pivotal Cloud Foundry and AWS.
- Migrated .Net & angular Application from on premise to Azure Web Application Service
- Leveraged Jenkins and Azure DevOps Pipelines for seamless transitions across diverse applications, including .Net Core, Java, Angular, and static web applications.
- Skilled in analyzing complex build, release, and deployment processes, writing YAML scripts for automation, and deploying ASP.NET Core MVC projects using Docker on Elastic Container Services.
- Proficient in security and code quality tools such as SonarQube, Black Duck, and Checkmarx.

Project Manager - DevOps

- Provisioned global region infrastructure efficiently with Azure ARM Templates on Azure Landing Zone.
- Demonstrated adeptness with foundational development tools and crafting complex pipelines using Azure DevOps.
- Proficiently created images and containers, orchestrated PODs, and maintained services and ingress using Azure Kubernetes.
- Managed various Azure resources including Key Vault, Resource Group, Service Bus, Containers, AKS, access policies, secrets, quota creation, and Pinning.

#### Capgemini, Pune/Budapest

Jul 2013 - Jun 2018

Senior Consultant

- Automation of Unix Admin tasks developing Bash scripts
- Use of ServiceNow and Kanban for incident management, change control and task management.
- Development of chef cookbooks with Jenkins for automation, CI/CD of managed products and related services
- Use of Github Enterprise and Git for control version and repository management.
- Worked on Amazon Web Services (EC2, ELB, VPC, S3, CloudFront, IAM, RDS, Route 53, CloudWatch).
- Experience in Apigee Middleware, SQL & No-SQL database server, RabbitMQ.

## Certification

**2021 AZ-900 MS Certified: Azure Fundamentals ITIL Foundation Certificate: GR750194063MS** 

**2022 CLF-C01 AWS Certifies: Cloud Practitioner New Relic Performance Pro Certified** 

## **Awards**

## **Hobbies**

Travelling, Video Editing, Playing Guitar

### **Personal Details**

Birth Year: 1990

Language: English, Hindi Marriage Status: Married

Address: 201, Gayatri Nagar, Nagpur, Maharashtra, 440022

<sup>&</sup>quot;Digital Warrior" Award 2023 for providing end to end solutions of DevSecOps using Github Action standalone.

<sup>&</sup>quot;Go the Extra Mile" Award 2021 for provided quick solution to a high severity incident.

<sup>&</sup>quot;Star Performer" Award 2018 for meeting the target deliveries of client and deployed APP in UK & Germany Region

<sup>&</sup>quot;Pat on the Back" in 2015/2017 for regular assignments given to me without losing any SLA.